<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-08-27T11:19:51-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">manilogs</title><subtitle>A round corner of the internet.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">time invariant problems</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/20/time-invariant-problems.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="time invariant problems" /><published>2022-06-20T10:48:31-06:00</published><updated>2022-06-20T10:48:31-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/20/time-invariant-problems</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/20/time-invariant-problems.html"><![CDATA[<p>A person educated enough in Roman life and history can probably easily close their eyes and imagine themselves in that environment. Understand the influences they would have been under and what level of general understanding of one’s surroundings they would have had. A very creative individual could probably even construct a snapshot of a mental image such a person would have, what opinions would prevale and what they would concern themselves with on a daily basis.</p>

<p>If you were to close you eyes now, you can imagine yourself, and a general picture of the human side of the environment equation, that is time invariat, you could be placed in an ancient Sumerian city, the Roman Republic or Empire, the 20th century or today. This time invariance of the human condition is, I believe, one of the main set of problems we have to deal with in order to evolve as a species. It doesn’t take a good understanding of history to see how we are repeating past mistakes. <a href="https://collabfund.com/blog/the-same-stories-again-and-again/">The same stories, again and again</a>. If we don’t work on the real problems, we have no hope for a brighter future, it will always be this little spark surrounded by darkness, a small hope of making it.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A person educated enough in Roman life and history can probably easily close their eyes and imagine themselves in that environment. Understand the influences they would have been under and what level of general understanding of one’s surroundings they would have had. A very creative individual could probably even construct a snapshot of a mental image such a person would have, what opinions would prevale and what they would concern themselves with on a daily basis.]]></summary></entry></feed>